# **ELIZABETH BETSON**

Chicago, IL 60610

Phone: (312) 523-6571 | Email: hire.elizabethb@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/elizabethbetson | Github: https://github.com/emariebetson |

Portfolio: https://emariebetson.github.io/responsiveportfolio/

#### SUMMARY

Accomplished full stack web developer with sales background and 5+ years of experience in biotechnology, marketing, and nonprofit expansion to create user-friendly, interactive experiences.

Exceptional leadership, public speaking and written communication (both English and basic Spanish), relationship-building, analytical, and problem resolution skills. Thrives in both independent and collaborative work environments and embraces a life-long dedication to continued learning.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | jQuery | Bootstrap | Express.js | React.js | Node.js | Database Theory | MongoDB | MySQL | Git | Javascript | React

#### **PROJECTS**

# BuzzKillR | Github | buzzkillr.herokuapp.com

- A social network for reporting and aggregating data about night life wait times and bouncer behavior.
- Front-End Development, Design
- Languages: Node, Express, React

## EcoCoat | Github | chicacoat.herokuapp.com

- A full stack web application that is an eco-friendly winter wear drop shipping alternative.
- Front-End Development, Design
- Languages: Node, MySql, Express, Sequelize, Passport

### Future Forecast Finder | Github | futureforecastfinder.com

- A front-end application that predicts climate change over time.
- Front-End Development, Design
- Languages: AJAX, Meteostat API, Graph.js

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

**UX & Interactive Designer DAC Management** 

2013 – Present Chicago, IL; Hong Kong

Communicated detailed technical medical and financial research to business owners and executive management team.

- Advanced quickly within the company, helping to recruit and hire new talent after demonstrating leadership skills and a self-starting initiative to aid in the acquisition of Medical Entrepreneurs II, Inc's groundbreaking cardiology biotechnology.
- Leads current expansion in API creation for competitive financial global markets.

# CTO, Front-End Developer Eco Preservation Project

2018 – Present

Chicago, IL; Miami, FL

Created interactive ecommerce and scheduling application for nonprofit charity (ecopreservation project.com).

• Increased profits and donations by over 3000% in past six months, earning promotion to C-level executive seat.

# UI Designer & Model Wilhelmina International

2001 - 2017

Global

Utilized dedicated autonomy and time-management skills to ensure both individual and industrial success.

• Promoted to create dozens of online portfolios for aspiring talent to drive bookings.

# ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Product Specialist Alma Lasers

2015 – 2017

Los Angeles, CA

Built robust client base and programmed route efficiencies to maximize potential customer outreach.

• Advanced from Sales Representative to Product Specialist, closing \$400,000 within six months with \$2 million actively working in pipeline.

#### EDUCATION

#### Bootcamp Certificate: Northwestern University, Chicago, IL

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor of Science in Biology, minor in Psychology (with Honors): DePaul University, Chicago, IL

Two-time published co-author for *Journal of Macromolecular Science, Part A: Pure and Applied Chemistry* 

Associates Degree, Certified Nurses' Aide: Labette Community College, Parsons, KS